Guide to the Frank Durkan Papers AIA.008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Legal Cases, 1975-2003
  - Subseries D. U.S. v. Harrison et al (George Harrison)
    - Memorandum of Law: Pre-Trial Motions, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Motion for a Bill of Particulars, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Motions I, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Motions II, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Motions, Final Drafts, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Motions for Discovery, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - National Jury Project, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - New Discovery, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Northern Ireland News Service, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Order Regarding Pre-Trial Procedure and Date of Trial, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Phone and Meeting Transcripts, 1980-1981 (Box 34, Folder 22, Folder 20, Folder 21)
    - Political Rights Defense Fund, Sep 1987 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Por La Paz y La Solidaridad, Apr 1987 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Press and Publicity, 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Press Releases and News Articles, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Puerto Rico, Aug 31, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Return of Bail and Property, 1968-1983 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 30, Folder 29, Folder 28, Folder 27)
    - Search Warrants, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Speeches at Various Functions and Rallies, 1982-1987 (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Speedy Trial, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 15, Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Subpeonas, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 33, Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Subpoenas Duces Tecum Application, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - Superceding Indictment, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Surveillance Logs, Apr 1981-Dec 1981 (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - FBI: Press Releases, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - FBI Surveillance: Supporting Documentation [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - FBI: Tapes and Transcripts 1/3, Apr 1981- Jun 1981 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - FBI: Tapes and Transcripts 2/3, Apr 1981- Jun 1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - FBI: Tapes and Transcripts 3/3, Apr 1981 - Jun 1981 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison I, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison II, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison III, 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison / DeMeo, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison / DeMeo I, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison / DeMeo II, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison et al, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Harrison et al, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Tom Falvey, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Tom Falvey / DeMeo, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - FBI: Transcripts - Tom Falvey / Harrison / DeMeo, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - FBI: Transcripts: Search Warrants I, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - FBI: Transcripts: Search Warrants II, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 1-374, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 375-530, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 1006-1019, 1473-1503, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 1020-1101, Oct. 6, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 1649-1708, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 1708-1927 (DeMeo Testimony), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 2001-2099, [1982] (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 2100-2188 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 2190-2298, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 2623-2662, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 2771-2847, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 3228-3271, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Trial Transcript pp. 3274, 3276-3433, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Post-Trial materials: Harrison personal note, Defense Committee members, jury verdict form, pictures, clippings, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Unemployment Insurance Interview, Jul 1981 (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - Expenses, Disbursements, Out of Pocket [RESTRICTED], 1982 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      Materials are open.
  - Subseries E. Individual Cases - Extradition /Deportation
    - Artt, Kevin Barry John, et. al.: Extraditees (Brennan, Kirby, Campbell), 1992-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Artt, Kevin Barry John, et. al.: Extraditees (Brennan, Kirby, Campbell), 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Attorney-Client Privileged Documents [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Barr, James Gerard: Deportation I, 1984-1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Barr, James Gerard: Deportation II, 1984-1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Doherty, Joe, 1983-1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Doherty, Joe: Sprizzo Decision, Dec 12, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - Feehan, Patrick, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - US. v. Flanagan, Martin (gunrunning), 1982 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - US v. Martin Fleming, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - Fort Worth Five, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 39)
    - Galvin, Martin (Noraid Lawyer), 1984 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - US v. Johnson, Maguire, Quigley, Reid, and Hoy: Correspondence and Memoranda [RESTRICTED], 1989-1995 (Box 37, Folder 13, Folder 14)
    - US v. Johnson, Maguire, Quigley, Reid, and Hoy: Press, 1989-1990 (Box 34, Folder 41, Folder 40)
    - US v. Johnson, Maguire, Quigley, Reid, and Hoy: Court Transcripts, 1989-1992 (Box 34, Folder 42, Folder 43)
    - Kelly, Nicky (includes chronology), 1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - King, Matthew, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Magahey, Gabriel: Application for Political Asylum I, 1979-1982 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Magahey, Gabriel: Application for Political Asylum II, 1979-1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Maguire, Patrick: deportation, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - McAllister Family Case: political asylum, 1997-2000 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - McKeon, Bernard (conspiracy to export firearms), 1979-1984 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - McKeon, Bernard and Olive, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - McKeon, Olive, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - McManus, Birdie / Shannon Travel Service: subpoena, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - McManus v. Doubleday: Libel Suit (Fr. Sean McManus, Redemptorist, founder of Irish National Caucus) I, 1975-1978 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - McManus v. Doubleday: Libel Suit (Fr. Sean McManus, Redemptorist; Founder of Irish National Caucus) II, 1975-1978 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - McManus v. Doubleday: Research and Information on Irish Nationalist, FBI files, 1974-1982 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - McMullan, Peter Gabriel John: Deportation/Extradition, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - McMullan, Peter Gabriel John: Deportation/Extradition, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: aka "Pete the Para"; Correspondence and Research, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: California Pleadings, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Decision, 1979-1981 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Exhibits I, 1975-1980 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Exhibits II, 1975-1980 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Exhibits, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Memorandum Decision, May 1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Post-hearing Memorandum, May 1979 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Reply Memorandum, Jan 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Reporters Transcript (court), Mar 26, 1979 - Mar 27, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Respondent's Appeal Brief, Mar 1980 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Statement of Facts (The Queen v. McMullan), 1978 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - McMullan v. U.S.: Witnesses, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Moloney and Millar v. U.S.: Clippings, Nov 1993 (Box 34, Folder 44)
    - Moloney and Millar v. U.S.: Correspondence and Memoranda [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Moloney and Millar v. U.S.: Court Transcripts, Nov 1993 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Moloney and Millar v. U.S.: Search Warrants, Nov 1993 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Moloney and Millar v. U.S.: Subpoenas, Nov 1993 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Mulhulland, Michael Dermot: Case file, Visa application, 1994-2000 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Murray, Tom, 1978-1983 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - O'Doherty, Edmond: Visa application, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - O'Muracu, Noel, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - O'Neill, Fogarty, McCormick, and O'Sullivan v. U.S., 1992-1993 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - O'Rourke, Michael (aka Patrick Mannion): Deportation, 1979-1984 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - O'Rourke, Michael (aka Patrick Mannion): Deportation; Free Michael O'Rourke Committee of Philadelphia, 1981-1983 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Passport Cases [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Passport Cases: "Manufacturing American Citizenship for Illegals", Jan 1988 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Pearson, Brian Desmond: Deportation, 1997-2000 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Quinn, William (Liam) / Balcombe Street Four: Deportation, San Francisco, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Quinn, John Herbert: illegal sale of firearms; (Mayor, Concord, NH), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Quinn, John Herbert: Newspaper Clippings, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Deposition and Exhibits, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Exhibits I, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Exhibits II, circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Interrogatories and Production Requests: Statement before House Committee of the Judiciary, 1981-1983 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Opinion and Order, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Opinion - Appeal Argued 1984, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Report of Trial, Clippings, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Warrant, Information, Depositions I, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Quinn, Wiliam Joseph: Extradition - Warrant, Information, Depositions II, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Smyth, James Joseph (Jimmy): Deportation case, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Smyth, James Joseph (Jimmy): Extradition, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Surveillance of Irish Americans, 1977-1978 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - U.S. v. Meehan et al (gun running), 1982 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - U.S. v. Murphy, Noel: Correspondence (aka Noel O'Murchu; gunrunning, Boston), 1986-1989 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - U.S. v. Murphy, Noel: FBI Transcript I, 1985-1987 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - U.S. v. Murphy, Noel: FBI Transcript II, 1985-1987 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - U.S. v. Murphy, Noel: FBI Transcript III (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Zaitschek, Laurence, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Deportees: Correspondence - Congress, President of the United States, 1996-2000 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Extradition Treaties: UK and US, 1931-2003 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Group A Deportees: "compendium of documents on deportees" Deportees are: Noel Gaynor, Robert McErlane, Gabriel Megahy, Matthew Morrison, Brian Pearson, Kevin Crossan, 1999-2003 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Group A Deportees: [file information], 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Group A Deportees: Gaynor, Morrison Decisions and Reno Suspension (correspondence), Oct 1996 - Dec 2000 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Group A Deportees: Press Clippings, 1993-1997 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Group B Deportees List, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Legal Immigration and Family Equity Act, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subseries F. Human Rights
    - Bloody Sunday: Irish Times Report - Widgery Tribunal, Jun 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Bloody Sunday Inquiry: Madden and Finucane, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Britain and Ireland Human Rights Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Finucane, Pat Case: Articles "Burying the Truth: The Murder of Belfast Human Rigths Lawyer Partick Finucae and Britain's "Secret" Public Inquiries," Jaoquin P. Eterceno, III. Fordham Law Review, Vol. 74; "Northern Ireland Update," Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Mar 1999 - Dec 2002 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Finucan, Pat: Helsinki Commission and U.S. Congressional Hearing, May 2004 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Finucane, Pat (Murder) - Ed Moloney (Journalist), Sep 1999 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Finucane, Pat: Pat Finucane Center, 2003-2006 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Fincane, Pat and Rosemary Nelson Assassinations, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Hearing: Human Rights "The Peace Process in Northern Ireland" - U.S. Congressional Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights of the Committee on International Relations, Oct 1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights Watch / Helsinki Report: "Policing in Northern Ireland", May 1997 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights Report: "Human Rights and Legal Defense in Northern Ireland: The Intimidation of Defense Lawyers; The Murder of Patrick Finucane", Feb 1993 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Nelson, Rosemary: Assassination - Reaction, Press Releases, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Nelson, Rosemary: Press, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Nelson, Rosemary: Report - Human Rights Watch, Mar 1999 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Northern Ireland Alert: Ranking of Congressional Members on Northern Ireland Human Rights, Sep 1997 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Report: British Irish Rights Watch - "Deadly Intelligence: State Involvement in Loyalist Murder in Northern Ireland, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Publication: At the Crossroads: Human Rights and the Northern Ireland Peace Process - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Dec 1996 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Shanaghan, Patrick: Murder/Inquiry, Sep 1996 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Thompson, Paul: Murder/Inquiry, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Subseries G: Outside U.S. (cases)
    - Columbia 3: Bring Them Home Campaign, Final Report (Niall Connolly, Jim Monaghan, Martin McCauley) I, 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Columbia 3: Bring Them Home Campaign, Final Report (Niall Connolly, Jim Monaghan, Martin McCauley) II, 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Columbia 3: Case Information, Individual Declarations, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Columbia 3: Observer Visit to Columbia (including Durkan), Nov 2002 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Columbia 3: Organization Action, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Columbia 3: Press Clippings, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Columbia 3: Trial Observation Briefing Packet, Nov 28, 2002 - Dec 5, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin: Denied U.S. Entry, Feb 2003 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - McAliskey, Roisin: Arrest, Detainment, Nov 1996 - May 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - McAliskey, Roisin: Arrest, Detainment, Jun 1997 - 1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - McKevitt, Michael: Press, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - McKevitt, Michael: Trial Summaries - New Republic Forum, Jun 2003 - Jul 2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - McKevitt, Michael and Bernadette: Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - McKevitt, Michael and Bernadette: British Irish Rights Watch Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Reynolds v. The Sunday Times - Albert Reynolds TD, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Sands-McKevitt, Bernadette: Visa Denial, Jun 1998 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Subseries H: Prisoners
    - Boston 3: Richard Johnson, Martin Quigley, Eammon MaGuire, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Brennan, Paul (Pol): Correspondence and Articles, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Campbell, Paul: Appeal, May 1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Irish American Families Against Political Deportations, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Irish Political Prisoners of War Committee: Newsletters (Clair Shores, NY), 1996 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Jensen, Lowell: Information (Attorney General, Justice Department), 1994 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Kelly, Nicky: Prisoner information packet, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Legal Communication, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Legislative Action and Resolutions: New York State, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Lists: Deportations and Extraditions, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Martin, Michael and Aidan Moley: Extradition UK to US, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - McGeough, Terence Gerard (Gerry), 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - McNamee, Danny: Irish Prisoners in the United Kingdom, Mar 1995 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Megahey, Gabriel: Legal information and related cases: Kevin Crossan, Robert McErlean, Oct 1995 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Morrison, Matthew, 1993-1994 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Prisoner Action Groups: Correspondence, Press, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Prisoner Article: "If You've Come a' Seeking Justice, No Irish Need Apply: Irish Republicans, Political Asylum and United States Foreign Policy." Karen McElrath in Critical Criminology, Dec 1997 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Profiles of Individual Prisoners, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Profiles, Request, Responses: Correspondence, Notes, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Quinn, William Patrick: Long Kesh Letter (fragile), undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Report: "Comparative Study - Release and Reintegration of Politically Motivated Prisoners in Northern Ireland." by Brian Gormally and Karen McEvoy. Northern Ireland Association for the Care and Resettlement of Offenders., Mar 1995 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Report: "The Situation of Irish Republican Prisoners in the U.K." British Irish Rights Watch, Mar 1997 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Sullivan, Bob and Denver O'Neill, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Tucson 6: Press Clipping, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Subseries I: Northern Ireland
    This series includes files and information on cases of interest and importance to Durkan taking place in Northern Ireland. Bobby Sands' hunger strike, the shooting of Lord Mountbatton and the use of Diplock Courts to put Irish in prison, as well as several files on John Stalker as well as the manuscript of his book "Stalked" which document the unofficial shoot to kill policy utilized by the northern police forces on Catholic Irish in Northern Ireland.
    - H-Block / Lord Mountbatton: Article, Correspondence, Plastic Bullets II, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - H-Block / Lord Mountbatton: Article, Correspondence, Plastic Bullets I, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - H-Block / Lord Mountbatton: Plastic Bullets, circa 1998 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike I (mostly newspaper clippings), 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike II, 1980-1982 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - Articles and Biographical information (poems), 1981 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - Articles and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Daily News clippings, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Post clippings, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Sands, Bobby: Hunger Strike - New York Times clippings, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry (Police Killings; Lawyer's Inquiry), 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Shoot to Kill Policy I, 1983-1989 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Shoot to Kill Policy II, 1983-1898 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Article - "Criminal Justice and Human Rights in Northern Ireland" in The Records of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Mar 1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Lawyers Correspondence I, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Lawyers Correspondence II, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Newspaper Clippings: Shoot to Kill, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Publication - "Shoot to Kill?: The Report of the International Lawyers Inquiry into the Lethal use of Firearms by the Secruity Forces in Northern Ireland." Mercier Press. Dublin/Cork., 1984 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Stalker, John Inquiry: Publication - book review of "Shoot to Kill?" Keara M. O'Dempsey. Seton Hall Law Review. Vol. 17, no. 1, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Stalker, John: "Stalked" loose papers, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Stalker, John: Stalked Newspaper Clippings, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Subseries J: Shah of Iran
    Materials in this subseries relate to the former ruling family of Iran and subsequent legal actions taken by the State of Iran against the family, suing them for their assets. These files relate to the Plaintiff who in this particular lawsuit was Ashraf Pahlavi, twin sister of the late shah of Iran, Mohammed Reza Pahlavi.
    As background, in January 16, 1979, the Shah and his wife, the empress, left Iran to live in exile after the overthrow of government and installation of Ayatollah, Ruhollah Khomeini. The Ayatollah, attempted to seek extradition from any country the Shah would visit or go to and also sought to seize all of the Shah's assets. The Ayatollah also called for the assassination of the Shan and numerous family members. The Shah came to New York City on Oct 22, 1979 for medical care and this visit led to the Iranian Hostage Crisis. After seeking refuge in other countries, the Shah finally settled in Egypt where he died July 27, 1980. The hostages were not released until January 20, 1981 after an agreement was negotiated, the Algerian Accords.
    The suit in these files refers to that brought against the royal family by the country of Iran. The case was brought to the attention of O'Dwyer and Bernstien when the Shah came to New York City for medical attention. In the opinion of the lawyers, the Ayatollah was attempting to continue its revolution in the courts of the United States by attempting to take from the Royal Family via judicial process what it could not take by force. Iran was asking the Unites States court to intervene in a political dispute between two ruling regimes in a foreign country: The Khomeini regime and the Pahlavi regime. Brian O'Dwyer argued that New York has no responsibility to provide the type of forum that the Plaintiff - the government of Iran – should be providing and therefore the suit was considered illegitimate.
    The Princess, Ashraf Pahlavi was known as an advocate of women's rights and the material documents her frequent travel to other countries promoting women's rights. She was exiled from Iran in 1951 because of her "political meddling and general objectionable behavior". She was allowed to return permanently in 1954 (See folder FOI Request Documents, 1946-1959).
    - FOI Request: Correspondence, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - FOI Request: The Shah, 1951: Background, 1948-1959 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - FOI Request: The Shah of Iran, 1957-1964 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, 1968-1973 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, Family, Iran, 1947, 1958-1964 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - FOI Request Documents: Shah of Iran, Family, Iran, 1977-1980 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pahlavi (twin sister of Shah), 1946-1975 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pavlavi, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - FOI Request Documents Department of State: Princess Ashraf Pavlavi, 1966-1979 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Legal: Islamic Republic of Iran v. Ashraf Pahlavi: Brief for Defendant-Appellant, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Legal: Islamic Republic of Iran v. Ashraf Pahlavi: Respondent's Brief, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Legal: Settlement of Claim: The Government of the Islamic Repuboica of Iran, Claimant; The Government of the U.S.A., Respondent; Submitted to the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, The Hague, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 5)